<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Hi I'm Thomas Nguyen]]></title><description><![CDATA[A website by Thomas Nguyen]]></description><link>https://thmsngyn.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 06:01:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Between the World and Me]]></title><description><![CDATA[In  Between the World and Me  by Ta-Nehisi Coates, he writes: “Black people love their children with a kind of obsession. You are all we…]]></description><link>https://thmsngyn.com/between-the-world-and-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thmsngyn.com/between-the-world-and-me/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Between the World and Me&lt;/em&gt; by Ta-Nehisi Coates, he writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Black people love their children with a kind of obsession. You are all we have
and you come to us endangered. I think we would like to kill you ourselves before seeing you
killed by the streets that America made.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to explore this quote by utilizing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplypsychology.org/maslow.html#:~:text=Maslow&amp;#x27;s%20hierarchy%20of%20needs%20is,hierarchical%20levels%20within%20a%20pyramid.&amp;#x26;text=From%20the%20bottom%20of%20the,esteem%2C%20and%20self%2Dactualization.&quot;&gt;Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs&lt;/a&gt; as a tool illustrate Coate’s philosophy regarding parental discipline. First I’ll touch on how his philosophy compares to my own. Then, I’ll analyze why this form of discipline might be influenced by Coates’s perceived lack of control over his child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coates’s description of behavior, discipline, and punishment within the black community is incomparable to my own philosophy. As a child of immigrant parents who sought refuge in a new country, there were many sacrifices that were made in order to thrive. These sacrifices meant that we may have lost control over some psychological needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needs relating to esteem and belonging were not nurtured because my parents worked tirelessly every day of the week. They didn’t have the time or energy to provide emotional support. Although unfortunate, we were still able to ascend the hierarchy of needs beyond that of black individuals in America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black people don’t have control over their safety and security because their bodies can be destroyed at the hand of the police. This is the reduction of their humanity by cutting away their basic needs, the foundation of Maslow’s Hierarchy. The level of parental discipline Coates explains is reminiscent of the novel &lt;em&gt;Beloved&lt;/em&gt; where “a mother best expresses her love for her children by murdering them and thus protecting them from the more gradual destruction wrought by slavery” [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murdering your child is an incomprehensible thought. Protecting your child from the gradual torture of slavery is instinctual. What if the only perceived solution to protect your child is through the incomprehensible? Perhaps Coates must do the incomprehensible, Coates must harshly discipline, to attempt to control what he ultimately cannot. I think that pondering this question sheds some light on how Coates’s philosophy in discipline is influenced by their lack of control over their own safety and the safety of their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You are growing into consciousness, and my wish for you is that you feel no need to constrict yourself to make other people comfortable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I would not have you descend into your own dream. I would have you be a conscious citizen of this terrible and beautiful world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To yell ‘black-on-black crime’ is to shoot a man and then shame him for bleeding.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sparknotes.com/lit/beloved/themes/#:~:text=Slavery&amp;#x27;s%20Destruction%20of%20Identity,former%20slaves%20even%20in%20freedom.&amp;#x26;text=Yet%20her%20children%20also%20have%20volatile%2C%20unstable%20identities.&quot;&gt;Themes of &lt;em&gt;Beloved&lt;/em&gt; by Toni Morrison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Sirens of Titan]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Sirens of Titan  by Kurt Vonnegut aims to explore morality and the purpose of life, effectively giving guidance on both themes. As in…]]></description><link>https://thmsngyn.com/sirens-of-titan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thmsngyn.com/sirens-of-titan/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sirens of Titan&lt;/em&gt; by Kurt Vonnegut aims to explore morality and the purpose of life, effectively giving guidance on both themes. As in, two &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=O_ZvDwAAQBAJ&amp;#x26;pg=PA294&amp;#x26;lpg=PA294&amp;#x26;dq=titanic+bluebirds+kurt+vonnegut&amp;#x26;source=bl&amp;#x26;ots=nL431ZLmLl&amp;#x26;sig=ACfU3U0QcdPtg7J9biQqhe1Pl5g25Vc54w&amp;#x26;hl=en&amp;#x26;sa=X&amp;#x26;ved=2ahUKEwivjfDF8ovqAhUCOH0KHe6mCFYQ6AEwAnoECAwQAQ#v=onepage&amp;#x26;q=titanic%20bluebirds%20kurt%20vonnegut&amp;#x26;f=false&quot;&gt;titanic bluebirds&lt;/a&gt; with one stone (sorry, I couldn’t resist).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Morality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The worst thing that could possibly happen to anybody … would be to not be used for anything by anybody.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatrice Rumfoord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, this quote goes against our innate understanding of how we should view and act in relationships with others. The term “used” has baggage and is commonly portrayed in a negative light. However, the context of the novel adds more color to Beatrice’s realization. In short, Beatrice along with all individuals living in the world have been used as a tool for another alien specie’s purpose—or otherwise, good ends to justify the mere means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatrice recognizes the immorality in how she and mankind have been treated, but she also understands that being used is an essential and desirable part of life. Vonnegut uses this context to build a divide between right and wrong. “In the end, the novel suggests that being used is not the problem—it’s actually a key part of a good life—it’s being used merely as means that is immoral and prevents flourishing” [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It took us that long to realize that a purpose of human life, no matter who is controlling it, is to love whoever is around to be loved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malachi Constant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote marries nicely with the previously discussed theme of morality. Fully aware that he is a victim of manipulation, Constant still finds solace in what he believes is the purpose of life. The beauty is in the acceptance of external influences, giving significance to their existence and perhaps necessity—while also remembering that purpose is a personal matter and above all else, he has autonomy to discover whatever he finds meaningful to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something fascinating happens at the end of the novel. Constant is finally able to find his best friend Stony Stevenson, someone he had been searching for throughout his journey. Stony comes to Constant during death in an hypnotic illusion conjured by Salo, the alien from another universe. Constant found his loved one, his purpose, but at what means?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://salo.iu.edu/index.php/freedom-purpose-and-morality-in-the-sirens-of-titan-shapshay-on-the-sirens-of-titan/&quot;&gt;Sandy Shapshay. Freedom, Purpose and Morality in The Sirens of Titan | Shapshay on The Sirens of Titan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hi]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello! Thanks for visiting my site, as a token of my appreciation, here’s a quote for you. “The master has failed more times than the…]]></description><link>https://thmsngyn.com/first-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thmsngyn.com/first-post/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello! Thanks for visiting my site, as a token of my appreciation, here’s a quote for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The master has failed more times than the beginner has even tried.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen McCranie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>