<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Hi I'm Thomas Nguyen]]></title><description><![CDATA[A website by Thomas Nguyen]]></description><link>https://thmsngyn.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 18:25:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The Sirens of Titan]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Sirens of Titan  by Kurt Vonnegut aims to explore morality and the purpose of life, effectively giving guidance on both themes. As in…]]></description><link>https://thmsngyn.com/sirens-of-titan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thmsngyn.com/sirens-of-titan/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sirens of Titan&lt;/em&gt; by Kurt Vonnegut aims to explore morality and the purpose of life, effectively giving guidance on both themes. As in, two &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=O_ZvDwAAQBAJ&amp;#x26;pg=PA294&amp;#x26;lpg=PA294&amp;#x26;dq=titanic+bluebirds+kurt+vonnegut&amp;#x26;source=bl&amp;#x26;ots=nL431ZLmLl&amp;#x26;sig=ACfU3U0QcdPtg7J9biQqhe1Pl5g25Vc54w&amp;#x26;hl=en&amp;#x26;sa=X&amp;#x26;ved=2ahUKEwivjfDF8ovqAhUCOH0KHe6mCFYQ6AEwAnoECAwQAQ#v=onepage&amp;#x26;q=titanic%20bluebirds%20kurt%20vonnegut&amp;#x26;f=false&quot;&gt;titanic bluebirds&lt;/a&gt; with one stone (sorry, I couldn’t resist).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Morality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The worst thing that could possibly happen to anybody … would be to not be used for anything by anybody.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatrice Rumfoord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, this quote goes against our innate understanding of how we should view and act in relationships with others. The term “used” has baggage and is commonly portrayed in a negative light. However, the context of the novel adds more color to Beatrice’s realization. In short, Beatrice along with all individuals living in the world have been used as a tool for another alien specie’s purpose—or otherwise, good ends to justify the mere means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatrice recognizes the immorality in how she and mankind have been treated, but she also understands that being used is an essential and desirable part of life. Vonnegut uses this context to build a divide between right and wrong. “In the end, the novel suggests that being used is not the problem—it’s actually a key part of a good life—it’s being used merely as means that is immoral and prevents flourishing” [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It took us that long to realize that a purpose of human life, no matter who is controlling it, is to love whoever is around to be loved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malachi Constant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote marries nicely with the previously discussed theme of morality. Fully aware that he is a victim of manipulation, Constant still finds solace in what he believes is the purpose of life. The beauty is in the acceptance of external influences, giving significance to their existence and perhaps necessity—while also remembering that purpose is a personal matter and above all else, he has autonomy to discover whatever he finds meaningful to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something fascinating happens at the end of the novel. Constant is finally able to find his best friend Stony Stevenson, someone he had been searching for throughout his journey. Stony comes to Constant during death in an hypnotic illusion conjured by Salo, the alien from another universe. Constant found his loved one, his purpose, but at what means?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://salo.iu.edu/index.php/freedom-purpose-and-morality-in-the-sirens-of-titan-shapshay-on-the-sirens-of-titan/&quot;&gt;Sandy Shapshay. Freedom, Purpose and Morality in The Sirens of Titan | Shapshay on The Sirens of Titan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hi]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello! Thanks for visiting my site, as a token of my appreciation, here’s a quote for you. “The master has failed more times than the…]]></description><link>https://thmsngyn.com/first-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thmsngyn.com/first-post/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello! Thanks for visiting my site, as a token of my appreciation, here’s a quote for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The master has failed more times than the beginner has even tried.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen McCranie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>